Contact

Washington, DC parada@ucdavis.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/javierparada (LinkedIn)

are.ucdavis.edu/ (Company) paradajavier.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Stata

Econometrics

Data Analysis

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)
French (Limited Working)

Honors-Awards

Best Masters Thesis Award 2015 Open Data Challenge

Publications

Poverty dynamics in rural Mexico: What does the future hold?

Javier Parada

Postdoctoral researcher at The World Bank Washington

Summary

I am an applied microeconomist specialized in the application of econometric methods for big data analysis. I am currently working on the application of remote sensing methods to measure changes in agricultural productivity due to violence and forced displacement in the Middle East.

Experience

The World Bank 2 years 8 months

Postdoctoral researcher
July 2020 - Present (5 months)
Washington, District of Columbia, United States

Fellows' program in Forced Displacement sponsored by the DFID-UNHCR-World Bank program "Building the Evidence Building the Evidence on

Protracted Forced Displacement: A Multi-Stakeholder Partnership".

Land Use and Conflict in the Middle East

South Asia Data Team

April 2018 - June 2020 (2 years 3 months)

Washington D.C. Metro Area

- Harmonization of household surveys and maintenance of South Asia Micro Database (SARMD)
- Construction, adjustment, and analysis of expenditures per capita for poverty and inequality measures
- Study of asset ownership, gender, urban/rural, education, demographic, labor, and housing characteristics
- Design and implementation of survey metadata collection tool to compare survey characteristics
- Preparation of Tableau visualizations and SARMD User Guidelines https://worldbank.github.io/SARMD_guidelines/

UC Davis

2 years 7 months

Teaching Assistant
June 2015 - December 2017 (2 years 7 months)
Davis, CA

Instructor at the Department of Agricultural and Resource Economics June 2017 - August 2017 (3 months)

Davis, California

Treasury Wine Estates
Grower Relations Harvest Intern - Napa
June 2017 - September 2017 (4 months)
Napa, California

Department of Agricultural and Resource Economics, UC Davis President of the Graduate Student Association October 2016 - September 2017 (1 year) Davis

UC Davis
Teaching Assistant
April 2014 - June 2014 (3 months)
Davis, CA

The World Bank Short Term Consultant September 2013 - December 2013 (4 months)

Education

University of California, Davis

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Agricultural and Resource

Economics · (2011 - 2018)

University of California, Davis

M.S., Agricultural and Resource Economics (2017)

Centro de Investigación y Docencia Económicas, A.C. Master of Science (M.S.), Economics · (2008 - 2010)

Tecnológico de Monterrey

Bachelor of Science (BS), Accounting and Finance · (2004 - 2008)